Finding Aid of the Society of American Archivists Records, 1935-2016
University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee Libraries, Archives Department
- Records, 1935-2016, UWM Manuscript Collection 172; 271.9 cubic ft. (385 boxes, including 16 audio cassettes and 33 videocassettes) 1 oversize folder 7,545 digital files (26.2 GB) 1 film reel 5 microfilm reels approximately 170 books and serial titles
  - 11. Members of the Society, 1938-1984, 200/11
    - 1. Small Collections, 200/11/01; 2.4 cubic ft. (3 boxes)
      - Elizabeth Hamer Kegan, 1974-1977
        - Committee on Committees, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 13)
        - Committee on Society's History and Archives, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 14)
        - Correspondence, General, pre-1969 and post-1976 (Box 3, Folder 16)
        - Funding Priorities Conference, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 15)
        - Priorities for Preservation Conference, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 17)
        - Professional Standards Committee
          - Additional Nominees, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 20)
          - Fellows, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 19)
          - General, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - Robert W. Lovett, 1959-1968
        - General Files: Committee on Uniform Archival Statistics, 1967-1968; Committees, 1959-1960; Annual Meeting Paper, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 21)
        - Class Material, Margaret C. Norton's Course on Archives, Columbia, 1940-1941 (Box 2, Folder 33)
        - Class Material, Ernst Posner's Archives Course, American University, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - Philip P. Mason, 1973-1974
        - Site Search Committee for Executive Director's Office, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - William D. McCain, 1961-1972
        - Publications, 1961-1972 (Box 2, Folder 32)
      - David C. Mearns, 1951
        - Address: "The Nitid Crimson," Annual Meeting, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - Howard A. Merritt, 1959
        - Schellenberg, Theodore, Lecture on Archival Instruction, 1959 (Archival Management Course) (Box 2, Folder 24)
      - Margaret C. Norton, 1973
        - Interviews and Correspondence of William Birdsall, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - Dolores C. Renze, 1952-1972
        - Committees
          - Education and Training, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
          - Preservation Methods (1968 Survey), 1968 (Box 1, Folder 9)
          - Professional Standards, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 13)
          - Professional Standards
            - Chair's Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 10)
            - Fellows Nominations, 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 11)
            - Fellows Nominations, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 12)
          - Seal for the Society, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 14)
          - State and Local Records, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 15)
          - State Archives, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 16)
        - Correspondence, General: Secretary of the SAA and Active Member: 1945-1947; 1949-1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
        - Council Member
          - American Archivist (Torch Press, Publications, Karl Trevor), 1952-1956 (Box 1, Folder 1)
          - Clark Papers Case, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 2)
          - Minutes and Working Papers, 1954-1956 (Box 1, Folder 18)
        - Miscellaneous Correspondence and Subject Files: 1952; 1963-1969 (Box 1, Folder 6)
        - Miscellaneous, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
        - Reading File
          - Correspondence (Outgoing): 1964 January-September (Box 1, Folder 3)
          - Correspondence (Outgoing): 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - Symposia, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Alan D. Ridge, 1965-1975
        - Annual Meetings, 1965, 1966 (Folder 26)
        - Committees
          - College and University Archives, 1965-1968 (Box 2, Folder 27)
          - Preservation Methods, 1968-Records Management, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 29)
          - Program, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 28)
          - Resolutions, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 30)
          - Terminology, 1972-1975 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - 2. Frank B. Evans, 1964-1975, 200/11/02; 1 cubic ft. (1 box)
      - Awards Committee: Gondos Subcommittee, 1968-1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Business Archives Committee: Communications to Members, Reports, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Business Archives Committee: Workshops, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Committee Reports (Select), 1968-1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Education and Training Committee: Correspondence and Working Papers, 1964-1973 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - International Archival Affairs Committee
        - American Archivist: International News and Abstracts, 1970-1975 (Box 1, Folder 14)
        - Archives Study Tour, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 12)
        - Archives Study Tour, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 13)
        - Correspondence and Working Papers, 1970 January-July (Box 1, Folder 6)
        - Correspondence and Working Papers, 1970 August-December (Box 1, Folder 7)
        - Correspondence and Working Papers, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
        - Correspondence and Working Papers, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 9)
        - Correspondence and Working Papers, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 10)
        - Correspondence and Working Papers, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - National Union Catalog of Manuscript Collections, Advisory Committee on (SAA Rep.), 1965; ALA/ACRL Manuscript Collecting Committee, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Personnel Questionnaire: "American Archivists & Their Society: A Composite View" (with Robert M. Warner), 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Program Committee, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Program Committee, 1973: Chairman's Files, Reports to Committee and Council (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - Public Records Standards Committee: Correspondence and Working Papers, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - Public Records Standards Committee: Joint NMA-SAA Committee, 1965-1974 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - State and Local Records Committee
        - Correspondence and Reports, 1967-1971 (Box 1, Folder 21)
        - Correspondence and Working Papers, 1967-1972 (Box 1, Folder 22)
        - Correspondence and Working Papers, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 23)
        - Correspondence and Working Papers, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 24)
        - Correspondence and Working Papers, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Terminology Committee, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - 3. Ernst Posner, Study of State Archival Programs and Publication of American State Archives, 1940-1966, 200/11/03; 7 cubic ft. (7 boxes)
      Box 8, which consisted of the bibliography of American State Archives on 4" x 6" index cards, was discarded in September 2003.
      - American State Archives
        - General Records of the Project, 1961-1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
        - Library Resources, Council on, 1962-1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        - President of the Society, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        - Treasurer of the Society, 1962-1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - Secretary of the Society, 1962-1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
        - Progress Reports, 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
        - Publication, 1961-1964 (Box 1, Folder 7)
        - Advisory Committee
          - General, 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 8)
          - Correspondence with Members: Radoff, Crittenden, Duniway, Hill, Holmes, 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 9)
        - Professional Standards Committee, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 10)
        - State Records Committee, 1958-1963 (Box 1, Folder 11)
        - Library Functions in the States
          - Survey of (Dr. Monypenny), 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 12)
          - Third Assembly on 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 13)
        - Health, Education, and Welfare, Department of-Survey, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 14)
        - American Society for Legal History, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 15)
        - Materials and Supplies, Expenses, Travel Plans and Expenses, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Director's Personnel File and American State Archives, Secretary's Personnel File, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - American State Archives
        - Director's Trophies, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 18)
        - Correspondence with Alabama-Georgia, 1962-1965 (Box 1, Folder 19)
        - Correspondence with Hawaii-Kentucky, 1962-1965 (Box 1, Folder 20)
        - Correspondence with Louisiana-Mississippi, 1962-1965 (Box 1, Folder 21)
        - Correspondence with Missouri-New York, 1962-1965 (Box 1, Folder 22)
        - Correspondence with North Dakota-Rhode Island, 1962-1965 (Box 1, Folder 23)
        - Correspondence with South Carolina-Wyoming, 1962-1965 (Box 1, Folder 24)
        - Archives Administration in the States, 1940-1962 (Box 1, Folder 25)
        - Archives Administration in the States, 1955-1960 (Box 1, Folder 26)
        - Regional Developments, 1954-1962 (Box 1, Folder 27)
        - Canadian Provincial Archives, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 28)
        - Alabama-Iowa (Box 2, Folder 1-19)
        - Kansas-Nebraska (Box 3, Folder 1-14)
        - Nevada-Utah (Box 4, Folder 1-15)
        - Vermont-Wyoming (Box 6, Folder 1-6)
        - Report
          - Preliminaries and Appendixes (Box 6, Folder 7)
          - Preliminaries and Appendixes, Comments (Box 6, Folder 8)
          - Bibliography (with Comments) (Box 6, Folder 9)
          - Chapter I
            - Drafts (Box 6, Folder 10)
            - Comments (Box 6, Folder 11)
          - Chapter II
            - Drafts of Post-Trip Reports
              - First Group (Box 6, Folder 12)
              - Second Group (Box 6, Folder 13)
              - Third Group (Box 6, Folder 14)
              - Fourth Group (Box 6, Folder 15)
              - Fifth Group (Box 6, Folder 16)
              - Sixth Group (Box 6, Folder 17)
              - Seventh Group (Box 6, Folder 18)
              - Eighth Group (Box 6, Folder 19)
            - Comments on Post-Trip Reports (Box 6, Folder 20)
            - Abstracts from Post-Trip Reports for Director's Personal Use (Box 6, Folder 21)
            - Alabama-Florida (Edited by Mrs. Buck) (Box 7, Folder 1)
            - Hawaii-Massachusetts (Edited by Mrs. Buck) (Box 7, Folder 2)
            - Michigan-Ohio (Edited by Mrs. Buck) (Box 7, Folder 3)
            - Oklahoma-Wyoming (Edited by Mrs. Buck) (Box 7, Folder 4)
          - Chapter III
            - First Drafts and Materials (Box 7, Folder 5-6)
            - Second Drafts (Box 7, Folder 7)
            - Edited by Mrs. Buck (Box 7, Folder 8)
            - Comments on (Box 7, Folder 9)
          - Chapter IV
            - First Drafts and Committee Copies (Box 7, Folder 10)
            - Second Drafts and Approved Version (Box 7, Folder 11)
          - Final Text
            - Title Page-Georgia (Box 7, Folder 12)
            - Hawaii-Montana (Box 7, Folder 13)
            - Nebraska-Utah (Box 7, Folder 14)
            - Vermont-Index (Box 7, Folder 15)
            - Munden, Ken: Comments and Queries (Box 7, Folder 16)
            - Page Proofs, Marked for Index (Box 7, Folder 17)
        - Report on Developments Connected with or Resulting from the Study & Publication of (Box 7, Folder 18)
        - Archival Developments Connected with or resulting from the Study
          - Alabama-Louisiana (Box 7, Folder 19)
          - Maine-New Mexico (Box 7, Folder 20)
          - North Carolina-Wyoming (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - 4. Leon deValinger, Jr., 1939-1966, 200/11/04; 1 cubic ft. (1 box)
      - Annual Meetings: 1939, 1957-1962, and 1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Clippings and Articles, Miscellaneous, 1957-1961 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Correspondence and Subject Files, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence and Subject Files, 1941-1945 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence and Subject Files, 1946-1950 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence and Subject Files, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence and Subject Files, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence and Subject Files, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence, General: 1957 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence, General: 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Correspondence, General: 1959 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence, General: 1964 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Correspondence, General: 1965 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - Correspondence, General: 1966 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - Correspondence, General: 1967-69 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - Directory of State Archival Agencies, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Dover Newsletter, 1959-63 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - Nominating Committee, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 14-15)
      - Nominating Committee, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - State Records Committee: Reports and Miscellaneous, 1956-1958 (Second Accession, 1988) (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Utilization of Archival and Educational Resources, Conference on, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 5. Eleanor McKay, 1971-1982, 200/11/05; 1 cubic ft. (1 box)
      - ACT, 1971-1982
        - Mailing Lists (Box 1, Folder 1)
        - Newsletter Material (Box 1, Folder 2)
        - Newsletters and Related Material (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Annual Meeting, 1976
        - Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 7)
        - Correspondence Regarding Paper and Session Reports (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Annual Meeting, 1979: Multimedia Cataloging Session (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Archival Facilities, Survey of, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Archival Processing Areas, Survey of (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Description PAG: Anglo-American Cataloguing Rules II (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - Finding Aids Committee
        - Correspondence, 1972-1979 (Box 1, Folder 22)
        - Subcommittee on User Access, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 6)
        - User Analysis Subcommittee (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Finding Aids, Inventories: Background Material, Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - Fundraising Committee, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - Inventories, Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - Nominating Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Processing Work Areas: Functionalism and Esthetics (SAA Paper), 1976-Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Program Committee
        - Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 10)
        - Working Papers (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Registers, Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - SAA, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - SAA, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - SAA, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - SAA, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - Status of Women Committee, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Women's Caucus Newsletter and Related Correspondence, 1975-1980 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - 6. William D. McCain, 1938-1952, 200/11/06
      See microfilm copy of correspondence in 200/09/04, box 1
    - 7. J. Frank Cook, 1966-1984, 200/11/07; 2.8 cubic ft. (4 boxes)
      Box 2, which consisted of copies of publications, was deaccessioned, date unknown.
      - General, 1966-1980 (Box 3, Folder 1-5)
      - General, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Interim Board for Certification
        - Certification by Petition, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
        - Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 3)
        - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 4)
        - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 5)
        - Correspondence with Readers, 1988-1990 (Box 4, Folder 6)
        - General File, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 7)
        - General File, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 1)
        - General File, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 2-3)
        - Historical Background (Ken Duckett's file), 1977-1986 (Box 5, Folder 4)
        - Petition Guidelines, 1988-1990 (Box 5, Folder 5)
        - Petition Preparation, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 6)
        - Regionals, Discussions (Eva Moseley's file), 1985 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Management for Archivists-SAA Seminar, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - "Private Papers of Public Officials" [American Archivist Paper]
        - Background (Box 1, Folder 7)
        - Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 8)
        - Drafts (Box 1, Folder 14-15)
        - Final Draft (Box 1, Folder 12)
        - Final Report of Public Documents Commission (Box 1, Folder 6)
        - NARS Independent Issue (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
        - National Study Commission on Records and Documents of Federal Officials - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 9)
        - Presidential Recordings and Materials Preservation Act (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - Public Documents Commission, Draft Legislation (Box 1, Folder 5)
        - Publications, Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 2)
        - Related Issues (Box 1, Folder 13)
        - SAA Resolution Supporting Public Ownership, Proposed - 1974 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Records Management and Records Appraisal at the Systems Level (SAA Session, 1981) (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Religious Archives Within the Archival Profession (SAA Session, 1984) (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - SAA and the Regionals: Disjunctive Symbosis (SAA Session, Chair, 1979) (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - SAA Western Canada Archival Study Tour (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - SAA Western Canada Archival Study Tour
        - Liaison and Archival Agencies (Box 3, Folder 12)
        - Lodging (Box 3, Folder 13)
        - Potential Participants (Box 3, Folder 14)
        - Sightseeing (Box 3, Folder 16)
        - Transportation (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - 8. William Moss, SAA China Tour 1981-1986, 200/11/08; .6 cubic ft. (1 boxes)
      - SAA China Tour 1982
        - Planning Documents, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
        - January to February, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        - March, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        - April, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - May to December, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
        - Trip Interfiles, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - SAA China Tour 1986
        - October to December, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 7)
        - January to March, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
        - April to September 1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
        - October to December 1985 (Box 1, Folder 10)
        - January to March, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
        - April to May, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 12)
        - June to December, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 12. SAA Foundation, 2012-2014, 200/12
    This subgroup includes the website of the SAA Foundation, which was established in 2012. Its purpose is to support and benefit the charitable and educational purposes of its sole corporate member, the Society of American Archivists.
    - SAA Foundation Webpage, 2012-2014
- Additions, 2001-2006, Accession 2010-018; .4 cubic ft. (1 box); Additions of Task Force on Electronic Publishing Chair's records (2001-2003), and Working Group on Electronic Publishing Chair's records (2003-2006).
- President Edie Hedlin Additions, 1993-1994, Accession 2014-035; 1.4 cubic ft. (2 boxes); Additions of records from Edie Hedlin's term as president of SAA, dating from 1993 to 1994. The bulk of the materials pertain to the appointment of the Archivist of the US. Also included are Council materials and various other files pertaining to SAA presidential matters. Collection also includes a number of additional accessions of electronic records. Contact the UWM Libraries' Archives Department for more information.
- Manuscript Repositories Section Additions, 2009, undated, Accession 2015-024; .1 cubic ft. (1 folder); Additions of Manuscript Repositories Section records.
- Archival Security Additions, circa 1976-1977, Accession 2015-038; .2 cubic ft. (1 box); Additions of an Introduction to Archival Security manual and some other materials pertaining to archival security, from circa 1976-1977.